<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data on </title>
    <link>https://datasingularity.org/tags/data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 13:19:26 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://datasingularity.org/tags/data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Data Visualization-Part 3</title>
      <link>https://datasingularity.org/post/an-introduction-to-data-visualization-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 13:19:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datasingularity.org/post/an-introduction-to-data-visualization-part-3/</guid>
      <description>In this last blog post on Introduction to visualization I would like to take you folks through Sarah Bird&amp;rsquo;s recreation of Gapminder&amp;rsquo;s - Health and Wealth of Nations that was presented by Hans Rosling at a TED conference. This is an iconic visualization from recent times, one which inspired me to use visualization as the main tool when working with Data.
In the last two posts of this series the empasis was on the importance of using visualization for understanding data and sharing information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Data Visualization-Part 2</title>
      <link>https://datasingularity.org/post/an-introduction-to-data-visualization-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 13:17:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datasingularity.org/post/an-introduction-to-data-visualization-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Hello folks, I hope you found part one of the introducution to visualization series interesting. In part one, the focus was on using visualization for analysing and understanding data. In this blog, we will re-emphasize on this aspect of data visualization.
Let me take you back in time to the early 19th century which saw a large scale change in the societal structures around the world. Slavery was abolished, and the Second Industrial Revolution led to massive urbanization and significantly higher levels of productivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Data Visualization-Part 1</title>
      <link>https://datasingularity.org/post/an-introduction-to-data-visualization-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 14:56:54 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datasingularity.org/post/an-introduction-to-data-visualization-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Data visualization refers to the technique used to understand and communicate data or information by encoding it as visual objects (eg., points, lines, maps or bars). It is a very important skill to possess when working with data and is an absolute must for all data analysts and data scientists. In this blog I will try and illustrate the importance of using visual objects to understand data and share Information.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>